https://www.hickoryfarms.com/company/privacy-policy.html

My Account
Your favorite gifts are going fast! Order now to get them in time for the holidays
Last Revised 6.30.2020
Your privacy is of utmost important to us.  This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) explains what personal information may be collected through our websites and other online services, how that information is used, to whom it is disclosed to, and what Hickory Farms, LLC. does to protect it.  This Policy applies to personal information collected through websites, mobile applications, SMS messaging, and other services of the Hickory Farms brands or lines of businesses that adopt, link to, or display this policy (collectively, the “Services”).  Hickory Farms, LLC., 311 S Wacker Dr., Suite 2030, Chicago, IL 60606 (“Hickory Farms,” “we,” ”us,” ”our”, or “HF”) owns and operates all Services and is responsible for this  Policy. For purposes of this Policy, “Personal Information” means information provided through the Services that reasonably relates to you as an individual user of our Services.  Personal Information includes information that can be used to directly identify you, such as your first and last name, your home or mailing address, and your email address.  Personal Information also includes information that indirectly identify you, such as your age, gender, as well as your preferences, tastes, etc., when coupled with your personally identifying information or other information.
What Personal Information We Collect, How We Use It and How We Share It
Information You Provide to Hickory Farms
By using our Services, you will actively provide Personal Information when you visit to do all of the things typically associated with online services.  Examples of the Personal Information we collect may include:
First and last name
Address
Phone number
Email address
Personal preferences
Responses to survey questions
Purchase and ordering information
Payment card numbers
Demographic information
When conducting transactions with Hickory Farms, we must collect some Personal Information in order to provide the Services to you.  We may collect information at other various places on our Services.  These services may include, but are not limited to:
Engaging with our website
Transacting on our website or point of sale
Subscribing to email offers and newsletters
Subscribing to mobile messaging offers,
Participating in in survey
Entering contests or sweepstakes,
Interacting with any individual HF representatives
Submitting a Contact Us form on our website
Submitting a Corporate Gifting Information Request form on our website
We may also collect information that you provide on our Services about other people you know.  For an example, you may provide a gift recipient’s Personal Information while processing your orders or maintaining an entry in your online address book to purchase a gift for later.
Automated Information Collection
In addition to the information that you provide to us, we may also collect information about you during your visit to our website or using our Services.  Your devices may provide location information, navigational and device information, such as:
device type
browser types and versions
hardware model
operating system and version
identification numbers assigned to your mobile device such as Advertising (IDFA) on Apple devices
Advertising id on Android devices
mobile network information
service provide identification
IP Address
the website or services in which you came
the website or services to which you navigate.
Technologies we implement include, but are necessarily limited to:
(a)    Cookies.  A “cookie” is a small data file transmitted from a website to your device’s hard drive.  Cookies are usually defined in one of two ways, and we may use both of them:
(1) session cookies, which do not stay on your device after you close your browser, and
(2) persistent cookies, which remain on your device until you delete them or they expire.
We use the following categories of cookies on our Website.
i.    Strictly Necessary Cookies.  These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the Website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have requested, such as maintaining a record of your purchased items (e.g. a shopping cart), cannot be provided.
ii.    Performance Cookies.  These cookies collect anonymous information on how people use our Website to help us understand how you arrive at our site, browse or use our Website and highlight areas where we can improve, such as navigation. The data stored by these cookies never shows personal details from which your individual identity can be established.
iii.    Functionality Cookies.  These cookies remember choices you make such as the country from which you visit our Website, your preferred language, and your search parameters. This information can then be used to provide you with an experience more appropriate to your selections and to make your visits to our Website more tailored to your preferences. The information in these cookies may be anonymized.   These cookies cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.
iv.    Targeting Cookies or Advertising Cookies. These cookies collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign.  The cookies are usually placed by third-party advertising networks.  These cookies remember the websites you visit and that information is shared with other parties such as Google Ad Network advertisers.
Of course, if you do not wish to have cookies on your devices, you may turn them off at any time by modifying your internet browser’s settings. However, by disabling cookies on your device, you may be prohibited from full use of the Website’s features or lose access to some functionality.
(b)    Web Beacons.  A Web Beacon is an electronic image. Web Beacons can track certain things from your computer and can report activity back to a web server allowing us to understand some of your behavior. If you choose to receive emails from us, we may use Web Beacons to track your reaction to our emails. We may also use them to track if you click on the links and at what time and date you do so. Some of our third-party marketing partners may use Web Beacons to track your interaction with online advertising banners on our Website.  This information is only collected in aggregate form and will not be linked to your Personal Information.  Please note that any image file on a webpage can act as a Web Beacon.
(c)    Embedded Web Links.  Links provided in our emails and, in some cases, on third-party websites may include tracking technology embedded in the link. The tracking is accomplished through a redirection system. The redirection system allows us to understand how the link is being used by email recipients.  Some of these links will enable us to identify that you have personally clicked on the link and this may be attached to the Personal Information that we hold about you. This data is used to improve our service to you and to help us understand the performance of our marketing campaigns.
(d)    Third-party Websites and Services.  We work with a number of service providers of marketing communications technology. These service providers may use various data collection methods to improve the performance of the marketing campaigns we are contracting them to provide. The information collected can be gathered on our Website and also on the websites where our marketing communications are appearing. For example, we may collect data where our banner advertisements are displayed on third-party websites.
(e)     Google Analytics.  The Website sends aggregated, non-Personal Information to Google Analytics for the purpose of providing us with the ability to conduct technical and statistical analysis on the Website’s performance.  For more information on how Google Analytics supports the Website and uses information sent from the Website, please review Google’s privacy policy available at: https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites.
How We Use Your Personal Information.  We use your Personal Information for a variety of purposes in providing the Services, including to:
Process your online or offline orders.
Open an online account at your request.
Personalize your online experience with content and offers that are tailored to your interests.
Provide customer service, whether it's responding to a request or following up on an order.
Include you in surveys and contests.
Enable you to post your content, such as comments, images or videos.
Facilitate networks of online social activity centered around our products and services.
Improve our Services, the manner in which offers are made on our Services, the purchase decisions of our visitors, and the interactions visitors have with our Services.
Improve your experience with our Services: for example, through faster, better, smarter, and more customized online interactions.
Enable you to interact with third-party content service providers, whether by linking to their sites, viewing their content within our online environment, or by viewing our content within their online environment.
Market our products and services that may be of interest to you—for instance, we may add you to the Hickory Farms’ email list when you make an online purchase or sign up to receive emails; or we may add you to Hickory Farms’ print-catalog list when you make an online purchase.
Create aggregated, pseudonymized or anonymized information for statistical purposes.
Fraud prevention and protection, security, and any legal inquiries where required by law.
Text Messaging
You may have the opportunity to receive SMS or "text" messages, pre-recorded voice messages or auto-dialed phone calls from Hickory Farms, its affiliates and related entities as well as third parties.   Such text messaging may be used to authenticate your identity or mobile device, as well as provide you informational or marketing updates about services or products you may have requested.  In providing your mobile device number or cell phone number to us, you knowingly consent to such communications from Hickory Farms or for Hickory Farms to use your cell phone number or mobile device number as disclosed in this Policy.  Furthermore, you agree and represent that you have the authority to to receive such communications at the telephone or mobile device number you provide to Hickory Farms, or from which you send such communications to us. You further acknowledge that no purchase is required to opt into this communications service, and you may opt out at any time by following instructions from Hickory Farms.
To discontinue receiving SMS messages from Hickory Farms at any time, reply STOP or text STOP to 225522 or call 1-800-391-0444. For help, reply HELP or text HELP to 225522 or call 1-800-391-0444.
Any such communications you receive from us will be administered in accordance with your preferences and this Policy.
Information Sharing.
Third party service providers and vendors.  We use third-party service providers and contractors to help handle parts of our business because of their expertise, resources, or scale. They help us do things like fulfill orders, process payments, provide some customer service through chat features, monitor activity on our Services, serve surveys and provide analysis from the surveys (which could be combined with Services usage analytics), maintain databases, administer and monitor emails, administer and send mobile messages, serve ads on this and other Services, and provide consulting services. Contractors may also assist us in hosting microsites, mobile websites and mobile applications where you may provide Personal Information about yourself and others you know; and where they may observe information about you in the same way as described above.
Compliance with law.  We may disclose specific information about visitors to our Services if we have a good-faith belief that it's necessary or authorized under the law or to protect our customers, the public, or our business.
Sale of our business.  In the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business assets (including in the event of a reorganization, dissolution or liquidation), including a brand or line of business, information about you may be one of the business assets that is transferred in connection with the transaction.
Advertising and Marketing.  In addition to processing your Personal Information in providing the Services, we may share your Personal Information to enhance your enjoyment of our Services or the services of other companies.
Advertising.  We may share your Personal Informationa with a third-party advertising partner and its service providers in order to deliver to you banner advertisements and other advertising tailored to your interests when you visit certain websites. Our advertising partner will make the data we provide anonymous.
For information about opt-out programs that these third party advertising companies participate in, and to opt out of the use of your website browsing data for interest-based advertising by companies that participate in these programs, click each of the following:
Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) Opt Out
Direct Advertising Association (DAA) Opt Out (Web Choices).
To opt out of ads targeted to your interests through the use of data collected from the mobile applications on your device, please consult the settings on your device. You can also click the preference icon that may appear on some of our advertising served through use of these technologies.
Advertising and Marketing Partners.  We may share information with advertising and marketing partners in order to measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns, identify advertisements that you may have already received, manage and deliver advertising on other websites you may visit, and to better understand your preferences and interests.
HF Marketing.  If you request additional information or make an online purchase from us, you may receive e-mail from us about online specials and other events. If you do not want to receive e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by sending an e-mail to us at cserv@hickoryfarms.com and telling us that you do not want to receive e-mail from our company. We never sell or trade e-mail addresses with companies outside the Hickory Farms family of brands, which includes Pfaelzer Brothers, California Delicious, and Gourmet Gift Concepts.
Direct Mailing.  If you supply us with your postal address online you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not want to receive mail from us in the future, please let us know by sending an e-mail to:  cserv@hickoryfarms.com.. Also, you may receive mailings from other reputable companies. You can, however, have your name put on our do-not-share list by also sending an e-mail to us at the above cserv@hickoryfarms.com. Please provide us with your exact name and address. We will be sure your name is removed from the list we share with organizations other than the Hickory Farms brands listed above.
We sometimes make our customer list available to carefully screened companies whose products or services we think you might enjoy. However, your e-mail address will NEVER be sold or given to any other companies. If you prefer not to receive other mailings, copy your mailing label exactly and mail to us at:
Mail Preference Service, Hickory Farms, LLC., Suite 2030, 311 S Wacker Dr., Chicago, IL 60606.
Accessing Your Information and Exercising Your Privacy Choices
You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number given on our website:
See what data we have about you, if any
Change/correct any data we have about you
Have us delete any data we have about you
Express any concern you have about our use of your data
Security
Hickory Farms is committed to maintaining safety and security for our web site users.  We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the Personal Information we collect through our Services against accidental, unlawful destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. We use tools that are designed to protect our Services. They include, but are not limited to web application firewalls, account authentication, account fraud protection, encryption and malicious code protections. While we implement the above security measures on this site, you should be aware that 100% security is not always possible.  Please report any suspected or actual compromise of your account credentials or any other suspicious activity to us at: privacy@hickoryfarms.com or by calling 1-800-648-8075.
Third-party Websites
This Policy does not apply to websites or other domains that are maintained or operated by third parties or our affiliates.  Our Services may link to third-party websites and services, but these links are not endorsements of these sites, and this Policy does not extend to them.  Because this Policy is not enforced on these third-party websites, we encourage you to read any posted privacy policy of the third-party website before using the service or site and providing any information.
Your California Rights
If you are a California consumer, as defined by the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018, you may be afforded additional rights with respect to your “Personal Information” as that term is explicitly defined under California law.  Any Personal Information we collect is collected for the commercial purpose of effectively providing our services to you, as well as enabling you to learn more about, and benefit from, our services and the services of others. You may exercise each of your rights as identified below, subject to our verification of your identity.
Access.  You may email us at privacy@hickoryfarms.com. or call us at 1-800-648-8075 to request a copy of the Personal Information our Website databases currently contain.
Prohibit Data Sharing.  When applicable, you may prohibit the sharing of your Personal Information by submitting a request via email to privacy@hickoryfarms.com or call us at 1-800-648-8075. In your request, please explain how you wish us to prohibit the sharing of your personal data, and which categories of third parties you want to prohibit from receiving your Personal Information.  When such prohibitions are not possible to provide our services to you, we will advise you accordingly.  You can then choose to exercise any other rights under this Policy.
Portability.  Upon request and when possible, we can provide you with copies of your Personal Information.  You may submit a request via email to privacy@hickoryfarms.com or call us at 1-800-648-8075. When such a request cannot be honored, we will advise you accordingly.  You can then choose to exercise any other rights under this Policy.
Deletion.  If you should wish to cease use of our Website and have your Personal Information deleted from our Website, then you may submit a request by emailing us at privacy@hickoryfarms.com or or call us at 1-800-648-8075. Upon receipt of such a request for deletion, we will confirm receipt and will confirm once your Personal Information has been deleted.  Where applicable, we will ensure such changes are shared with trusted third parties.
We do not sell your Personal Information. If we ever decide to sell Personal Information, we will update you via this Policy and include a link entitled “Do Not Sell My Personal Information,” to provide You with an opportunity to opt out of sales of your Personal Information.
In addition, if a California resident exercises his or her rights under California law, including the CCPA, we shall not discriminate against that California resident by denying our goods or services, charging different prices or rates to similarly situated consumers, providing a different level or quality of our goods or services, or taking any other adverse action.
Third Party Marketing.  As disclosed above in this Policy, you have the right to opt out of all of HF’s sharing of your personal data with any third party for the purposes of that third party’s marketing its good or services to you.
This information is also maintained at: California: Your Privacy Rights
Users in the European Union
If you access our Services from the European Union, you may be afforded additional rights under the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).  The legal basis for our processing of your personal data in connection with our Services is Art. 6.1(b) of the GDPR, which allows processing of Personal Information, or “personal data,” as necessary for the performance of a contract. When you access our Services, you form a contract with us based on our Terms of Use, and we need to process your personal data to respond to your requests, ship products to you and satisfy our obligations with respect to the other purposes listed in this Policy.
As exceptions, we rely on your consent with respect to cookies per Art. 6.1(a) GDPR, and legitimate interests under Art. 6.1(f) EU GDPR, especially with respect to situations where we must process your personal data to comply with applicable laws (as a U.S. based company, we are subject to U.S. laws and must comply, just like EEA-based companies have to comply with EEA laws).
When you access our Services, you transfer your personal data to the United States of America for which the European Union Commission has not yet issued an unlimited adequacy decision.
We will process and keep your Personal Information for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy, for our legitimate business needs, and for compliance with applicable law.
You have a right to request from us these EU GDPR rights concerning your personal data: access to data; rectification of data; erasure of data; restriction on processing; objection to data processing; and data portability. You can exercise these rights through a combination of actions: accessing the information in your account; exercising your opt-out options through our Services; and by calling 1-800-648-8075 or email us at: privacy@hickoryfarms.com.
If you have provided consent for direct marketing emails or other data processing, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal.
You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority.
We do not use automated decision-making, including profiling, as referred to in Article 22(1) EU GDPR, that is, in a way that produces legal effects concerning you or significantly affects you. Our Services’ customization technologies and e-commerce processes are automated, but do not produce legal effects or affect you significantly as contemplated by Art. 22(1) or (2) GDPR.
Changes to this Policy
If we make any changes to this Policy, a revised Policy will be posted on this webpage and the date of the change will be reported in the “Last Revised” block above. You can get to this page from any of our webpages by clicking on the “Privacy Policy” link (usually at the bottom of the screen).
Conditions of Use and Contact Information
Any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and our Terms of Use. Please direct any questions or concerns regarding this Policy to:  privacy@hickoryfarms.com or by calling 1-800-648-8075.
